Boris Palacios

+573004117622

bpalaciosa@gmail.com

Certified Java Programmer (SCJP) And Certified Oracle Database, has more than 6 years of experience in Java technology, has worked in several companies where he has learned and developed his skills in software development and implementation. He has strong knowledge in development and testing of software components.

Skills:

- Java Standard

- Flutter Spring Boot
- Junit

- Html, CSS, JS
- Java EE
- PL/SQL DBA
- XML, JSON,
- **CSV**

- Oralce,
- MySQL,
- **Postgres**
- Seismic Data
- Scrum
- **AWS**

Languages

- Spanish (native speaker)
- •English (B2)

Experience

GRUPO CINTE – EXPERIAN – MI Data Crédito Empresas Bogotá, Colombia

Jun. 2019 – Present Java Developer

- Developer of the system integration modules with Payu
- Administration and development of the Dev, Qa, Prod database
- Java technology, Integration with service buses, SOAP, Data conversions from XML to JSON

HALLIBURTON

Bogota, Colombia

Aug. 2018 – Jun 2019

FullStack - Java Developer

- Development, application support. Development of the application for Peru Petro.
- Analysis of seismic data implementing algorithms of data analysis with Java / c ++.
- Maintenance and administration of Oracle and Postgres databases.
- Development of new software components with Spring Framework and Angular / React.
- For the Ecopetrol project worked with C++ and Java to read seismic data, and data from wells.

CARECLOUD

Bogota, Colombia

Feb. 2018 – Aug 2018

FullStack Developer

- Senior Java EE Developer, Help and Support to development team
- Development of Local Check list system for Infolaft, which will allow all banking or insurance entities to know their counterpart and mitigate risks.
- System developed under Java Enterprise Edition architecture using Spring Framework. And its components, such as Security, Rest, Data, etc.

CHUBB - Cognizant-ManPower, Bogota, Colombia

Sep. 2017 – Dic 2017

Java Developer

Worked as a Java developer in the BrigeLayer business project, which was responsible for making connections with different systems through web services. This system interconnected the countries Chile, Argentina, Panama, Peru and Colombia.

- Senior Support and maintenance of the system for Chubb ACE SEGUROS. -MANPOWER-COGNIZANT
- Solution of incidents and development of new functionalities.
- Analysis of requirements and development.
- Maintenance and data management.
- Used Technologies
- Java EE, SOAP, Rest
- Tools: Eclipse, MasterData, SoapUI Application server, SQLServer, DB2

CSI GROUP

Bogota, Colombia

Jan. 2016 - May 2017

Java Developer

Worked as a Java developer on the Axis and Ithaca projects, large software projects that are responsible for maintenance and insurance processes. Companies in the area of insurance like Liberty, Confianza.

- I participated in the project for Liberty insurer resolving incidents and creating new functionalities and modifications depending on the client's requirements.
- I participated in the project of the insurance company Confianza where initially solving incidents, then I started to participate in new developments in the area of portfolio, reinsurance, and people management.
- Used Technologies: Servlet, JSP, JavaScript, Css, Java, PL/SQL, SQL, SVN, GIT, Vaadin, EJB, JPA, Hibernate, Spring Framework, Struts Framework

INNOVAR TECNOLOGIA SAS, Bogotá, Colombia

June. 2014 - Nov 2015

Java Developer

- In the project for the Ministry of National Education, I had the opportunity to start from the beginning and to the end.
- I was part of the team along with the project Architect in the study and selection of technologies to use for the project, research pro and cons of each of the tools, we began the development reusable components avoiding the redundancy of code.
- When entering the project of the School Rodrigo Lara Bonilla this already was in the 70% of development. In this project I was able to participate in new functionalities that had been requested by the client, this project had a series of reports which were delivered in its entirety.
- Used Technologies: EJB 3 JPA 2, Hibernate 4, JSF 2, Primefaces 5, Maven, Subversion, iReport Framework, Struts Framework, Css, Html, JavaScript, Sql

LomincoSoft S.A.S- INNOVAR TECNOLOGIA SAS Bogota, Colombia

Oct. 2013 - May 2014

Java Developer

- In the project for Ministry of National Education I participated with the project architect for the selection of technologies and revision of documents for the development of Mockups a.
- Worked in development team extending the functionality of the existing system, as well as creating new functionalities that were generic, reusable and dynamic to the client.
- Used Technologies: EJB 3 JPA 2, Hibernate 4, JSF, Primefaces 5, Maven, Subversion, iReport Framework, Css, Html, JavaScript, Sql, RichFaces, Maven

I2B Technologies Colombia S.A.S Barranquilla, Colombia

Nov. 2012 – May 2013

Java Developer

- In this project, the Walmart Chile system was supported under the Oracle ATG Commerce system for Walmart Chile (leader.cl), new functionalities were created, and support was given to existing functionalities.
- Used Technologies: ATG Web Commerce, Serlvet, JPS, JQuery, JavaBeans, JBoss

Righthand Barranquilla, Colombia

Aug. 2012 – Nov 2012

Java Developer

• In this project I had the opportunity to be part of a team where we developed new functionalities for the Saintec Dental Clinic in the city of Barranquilla, we used Google technology for graphic interface as it provided security and robustness. Used Technologies: Java, JSP, Servlet, EJB3, JPA, GWT

GIFP

Barranquilla, Colombia

Aug. 2011 – Mar 2012

Java Developer

 I made the functionality of this system that allow users to search the auto parts they wanted to buy, the software allows them to perform such consultation filtering by vehicle brand and models. Used Technologies: Java, Hibernate, Swing, JPA

American System Barranquilla, Colombia

Aug. 2011 – Sep 2012

Java Developer

In this project the main objective was initially to migrate the functionality of an application made in Java Applet of which we hadn't the source code and migrate it to a Web application.

- I worked creating new functionalities required by the client, the system is in its operation allowing teachers to enter and Schedule their courses, and students enter and schedule their schedules and different academic activities.
- Used Technologies: Java, Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Groovy/Grails, JQuery

Datasysworld Barranquilla, Colombia

Feb. 2011 – May 2012

Junior Php Developer

- Taking of requirements, weekly meetings with the client, and creation of the different modules.
- Creation and maintenance of the database and issues solving. Used Technologies: Php, Javascript,
 JQuery, Html

SALUDCOOP EPS

Barranquilla, Colombia

Aug. 2010 – Feb 2011 Systems Assistant

- Taking of requirements, weekly meetings with the client, and creation of the different modules.
- Creation and maintenance of the database and issues solving. Used Technologies: Php, Javascript, JQuery, Html

Education

Universidad Nacional Abierta y A Distancia, Barranquilla, Colombia Systems Engineering	Jan. 2014 – Jun. 2019
SENA, Barranquilla, Colombia Technologist Analysis and Development of Information Systems	Oct. 2008 – Sep. 2010
Don Bosco Social Center , Barranquilla, Colombia System technique	Jan. 2007 – Sep. 2008
Sun Microsystems, Barranquilla, Colombia Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP)	Jun. 2010
Microsoft, Barranquilla, Colombia Microsoft Certified Professional: ASP.NET and Microsoft Framework 3.0	Mar. 2009
Oracle, Barranquilla, Colombia Oracle Database 10g: Administration I	Mar. 2009
Oracle, Barranquilla, Colombia Oracle Database 10g: Administration II	Apr. 2009

Further courses

Website Programming With Html And Javascript April 2010 - May 2010

Java - Development of Applications with Handling of Text Files and Handling of Exceptions March 2010 - April 2010

Java - Application Development with Simultaneous Process Handling and Menu Usage February 2010 - March 2010

Java - Application Development with Graphical Interface, Handling Events, Classes and Objects February 2010 - March 2010

Java - Application Development with Data Management in Memory June 2009 - July 2009

Java - Development of Applets / Applications using Database, Networks, Servlets and Multimedia June 2009 - July 2009

Java - Variables and Control Structures in Object-Oriented Programming: February 2009 - March 2009